准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
粉色的失败者
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
裤头村
欢迎来到裤头村
Welcome to Bikini Bottom
在这能找到海洋生物的最好标本
where can be found
some of the finest specimens of undersea life
你也知道
Well, you know
邮件
一座奖杯
An award?
我以前从来没得过奖
I never got an award before
石头你看
Look, rock
我得奖了
I got an award
小水母  我得奖了
Jellyfish, I got an award
小岛  我得奖了
Island, I got an awa--
我必须给海绵宝宝看看
I gotta show SpongeBob
不要动  小蜗
Hold still, Gary
就快好了
Almost done
海绵宝宝  你猜怎么着
Hey, SpongeBob, guess what?
我得奖了
I got an award
太好了  派大星
That's great, Patrick
是什么的奖
What's it for?
自己看吧
See for yourself
颁发给杰出成就的成就
For outstanding achievement in achievement--
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
SpongeBob SquarePants?
这拼写我名字的方式好奇怪
That's a funny way to spell my name
派大星  我觉得
Patrick, I think
这奖杯应该是我的
the award is for me
你肯定是误拿了
You must have got it by mistake
可这很闪亮啊
But it's shiny
是
Yeah
可你知道还有什么东西是闪亮的吗
But you know what else is shiny?
冰淇淋
Ice cream
太对了
Exactly
我找得到
I can find it
在这里头吗
Is it in here?
别  那是我
No, don't, that's my--
装奖杯的壁橱
award closet
我想要得奖
I want an award
派大星  别哭了
Patrick, don't cry
总有一天你也会得奖的
You'll get an award one day
我不可能会得奖的
I'm never gonna get an award
因为我什么事都没做成
because I've never done anything
可你是派大
But you're Patrick--
星
Star
你可以想做什么就做什么
You can do anything you want
你说得倒轻巧
That's easy for you to say
你可是海绵宝宝
You're SpongeBob
派大星  要是你想要得奖的话
Patrick, if you want to win an award
就必须要做事
you have to do something
我想要打败巨猴人  拯救第九次元
I want to defeat the giant monkey man
and save the ninth dimension
我也想
Me too
不过听起来有点小难
But that sounds a little hard
要不先从小点的事情开始好不
Why don't we start smaller?
我要打败小猴人  拯救第八次元
I wanna defeat the little monkey man
and save the eighth dimension
小点
Smaller
医生
Doctor
小点
Smaller
消防员
Fireman?
你能想到最小的事
The smallest you can think of
在蟹堡王上班
A job at the Krusty Krab?
对
Yeah
我上班期间时时刻刻做事
I do things at work all the time
那就出发吧
Then let's go
天啊  蟹老板能让我上班人可真好
Boy, it was sure nice of Mr. Krabs to give me a job
蟹堡王
而且工资还是五十块一小时
And at $50 an hour, too
我开始在这上班的时候
When I started working here
我得付蟹老板一百块一小时
I had to pay Mr. Krabs $100 an hour
嘿  章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
猜猜谁入职了
Guess who just got a job?
猜猜谁离职了
Guess who just quit?
我现在得奖了吗
Do I get my award yet?
你必须要努力争取才行  忘了吗
You have to work for it, remember?
真该死
Tartar sauce
接单
Pick up order
我现在得奖了吗
Do I get my award now?
没有
No
你必须把托盘带给顾客
You have to take the tray to the customer
好的
Okay
差一点
Almost
再试一次
Try again
这次要确保食物端到桌上
And this time, make sure the food gets to the table
像这样吗
Like that?
不对
Nope
见鬼
Barnacles
还是试点别的吧
Let's try something different
此处点餐
你只要接电话就行了
All you have to do is answer the phone
遵命船长
Aye-aye, captain
这是蟹堡王吗
Is this the Krusty Krab?
不  这是派大星
No, this is Patrick
这是蟹堡王吗
Is this the Krusty Krab?
不  这是派大星
No, this is Patrick
这是蟹堡王吗
Is this the Krusty Krab?
不
No
这是派大星
This is Patrick
我才不是蟹堡王
I am not a Krusty Krab
派大星  那是这家餐厅的名字
Patrick, that's the name of the restaurant
蟹堡王
该死
Fish paste
三号桌那边积了点灰
It looks a little dusty around table three
要不你来打扫一下好吗
How about if you sweep it out?
有什么意义
What's the point
我什么事都做不好
I can't do anything right
你能行的
You'll do fine
兄弟
Hey, pal
什么风把你从傻子镇吹来的
You just blow in from stupid town?
再接再厉  派大星
Keep trying, Patrick
我有一堆给海绵宝宝的奖杯
I got a load of awards for SpongeBob SquarePants
凭什么我什么事都做不好
Why can't I do anything right?
厨房
Kitchen
我现在是得不到奖的了
I'm never gonna get an award now
不要放弃  派大星
Don't give up, Patrick
这回我有件事你绝对可以做到
This time I've got something I know you can do
我们要开罐子
We're gonna open a jar
简单
Easy
现在你试试吧
Now you try
首先  拿罐子
First, get a jar
派大星  那是腌椰菜
Patrick, that's a pickle
对
Yes
你需要罐子
You need a jar
不对
No
试试这个
Try this
现在把盖子从罐子上拿下来
Now, take the lid off the jar
放轻松
Just relax
抬起你的手
Lift your hand
太棒了
Great
就快好了
We're almost there
把手放到盖子上
Now put it on the lid
不对  盖子
No, the lid
盖子
The lid
The lid--
不要动
Freeze
就快好了
Almost there
手伸向盖子
Now head for the lid
远了
Cold
近了
Warmer
很近了
You're hot
非常近了
You're on fire
近到烫死了
It burns
好了  好了
OK, OK
等下  等下
Wait, wait
照着我的样子做
Do exactly as I do
照着我的样子
Exactly as I do
照着
Exactly--
照着你的样子做
Exactly as you do
不好了  我弄坏了
Oh no, I broke it
不对  派大星
No, no, Patrick
你打开了
You did it
打开了
I did?
触地得分
Touchdown
我是开罐大师
I'm jar master
那可太棒了  派大星
That was great, Patrick
你真的已经掌握要领了
You really got the hang of it
好耶
Yeah
记得我刚刚把手举起来
Remember when I had my hand up
放到盖子上吗
and I put it on the lid?
记得
Oh, yeah
然后我把盖子拿下来
And then I took the lid off
我以为弄坏了
And I thought I broke it
是
Yeah
可我没有
But I didn't
我用手打开了罐子
I opened the jar with my hand
全都是因为你给我示范了怎么做
And it was all because you showed me how to do it
我不会忘记这个的
I'm never gonna forget this
派大星  你就照着我的样子做
Patrick, you do exactly what I do
你迟早会得奖的
and you'll have an award in no time
我准备好了
I'm ready
早上好  海绵宝宝
Good morning, SpongeBob
真的好神奇能看到简单换件衣服
It's amazing how a simple change of clothes
能让别人看起来
can make a guy look--
跟我一个样
just like me
没错
Yup
我要是想要赢得奖杯
If I'm gonna be an award-winner
就必须穿得像个赢得奖杯的人
I've gotta dress like one
看着不舒服
That's creepy
不过话说得挺好听
But flattering
我准备好了
I'm ready
蟹堡王
又要上班了
Well, back to the old grind
忘戴帽子了
Forgot my hat
我也是
Me too
锅铲掉了
Dropped my spatula
我也是
Me too
你在模仿我
You're copying me
没错
Yes
你为什么要那样
Why are you doing that?
这样我就能得奖了  像你一样
So I can win an award, like you
这样很烦
Well, it's annoying
就别这样了
So stop it
别这样了
Stop it
你可不错了
Say, you're good
谢了
Thanks
该死
Darn
玛丽有只小羊羔
Mary had a little lamb
它的绒毛白如
whose fleece was white as
腌椰菜鱼唇
pickled fish lips
邪恶海藻
Seaweevil
有鸡说鸡
Yorgie shmorgies
起码我内心是安全的
At least I'm safe inside my mind
别再模仿我了
Stop copying me
这样得不了奖
There's no award for that
现在大概可以进去了
Well, I guess it's safe to go in now
派大星  你还要继续这样多久
Patrick, how long are you gonna keep this up?
直到我得的奖跟你一样多为止
Until I have as many awards as you
那就走着瞧
We'll see about that
就不走
No we won't
我是裤头村跳绳冠军
I'm the jump rope champion of Bikini Bottom
我也是
Me too
是吗
Oh yeah?
我管这招叫切割跳
I call this one the slice and dice
一条划痕都不留
Not a scratch on me
别想逃
No you don't
当我当得没意思了是吗  派大星
Not much fun being me now, huh, Patrick?
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding?
我模仿你之前很早就开始做这个了
I used to do this way before I started copying you
轮到我了
My turn
真希望能让原本的派大星回来
I wish I had the old Patrick back
可他净是想要跟我一样
But he just wants to be like me
嗨  我是派大星
Hi, I'm Patrick Star
我是全裤头村最懒最粉的海星
I'm the laziest, pinkest starfish in Bikini Bottom
好希望我是我自己  不是海绵宝宝
and I wish I were me, and not SpongeBob
当个粉色的失败者有什么了不起的
What's so great about being a big pink loser?
没错
Exactly
我离得奖的距离就没有
I was never closer to an award
比我开始学你的那一分钟还近过
than the minute I started copying you
可是派大星
But Patrick
派大星不在
Patrick's not here
奖杯快递
Trophy delivery
又一个奖杯
Another trophy?
太棒了
Oh, great
这回又是什么的奖
What's it for this time?
颁发给什么事都不做的时间最久的
For doing absolutely nothing longer than anyone else
派大星
Patrick
这奖杯是给你的
This trophy's for you
耶
Yay
那你现在要做什么呢
So, what are you gonna do now?
我要保住我的荣誉称号
I'm gonna go protect my title
你觉得我是在开玩笑吗
So you thought I was kidding, huh?
不  在裤头村
No, in Bikini Bottom
就连石头下都能发现优秀
excellence can be found even under a rock
裤头村
泡泡人
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
配音  邋遢石斑
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
每天都是海绵宝宝的节日
Every day is a holiday for SpongeBob
即使他要自己编一个
even if he has to make one up
大家好  今天是莱弗埃里克松节
Hey, everybody, it's Leif Erikson Day
[ 莱弗·埃里克松：维京人，
第一个发现北美洲的欧洲探险家 ]
辛格丁格杜根
Hinga dinga durgen
[ 模仿维京人口音，无实际意义 ]
嘿  派大星
Ahoy, Patrick
今天是莱弗埃里克松节
It's Leif Erikson Day
有张字条
There's a note
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
我去找更多大纸张了
went to get more giant paper
派大星
Patrick
备注
PS--
莱弗埃里克松节快乐
happy Leif Erikson Day
耶格亨得登革
Yerger hernder dernger
[ 模仿维京人口音，无实际意义 ]
那就这样吧
So much for that
可能珊迪会来跟我玩
Maybe Sandy will play with me
又一张字条
Another note
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
去南方过冬了
went south for the winter
爱你的珊迪
Love, Sandy
我不明白了
I don't get it
水温刚好啊
The water's fine
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
要来玩吗
Wanna play?
不
No
你确定吗
Are you sure?
对
Yes
可真是
Darn
真希望能有个陪我玩的人
I wish I had a buddy to play with
有了
I know
直接造一个
I'll make one
木棍人
Stick buddy
不行
Nah
石头人
Rock buddy
不好
Nope
水池人
Sink buddy
差点感觉
Almost
有了
I've got it
泡泡人
Bubble Buddy
这
This
好
is
棒
great
蟹堡王
我等不及要让你
I can't wait for you to
认识认识章鱼哥跟蟹老板了
meet Squidward and Mr. Krabs
别害羞
Don't be shy
来吧
Come on
此处点餐
下次再来
Please, come again
等我不上班的时候来
when I'm not working
下一个
Next
嗨  章鱼哥
Hi, Squidward
要是你还是要过来上班的话
How am I supposed to enjoy your day off
我还怎么享受你的假期
if you come to work anyway?
我想让你认识认识我的新朋友
I want you to meet my new friend
泡泡人
Bubble Buddy
这泡泡是你朋友
This bubble is your friend?
他好帅气
Well, he's handsome
这点我承认
I'll give him that
还有什么事
What'll it be?
我不饿
I'm not hungry
那就谢谢惠顾
Well, thanks for stopping by
等等
Wait
你还没接泡泡人的单
You haven't taken Bubble Buddy's order yet
我凭什么要接
Why would I do that?
他饿了
He's hungry
他是没有生命的物体
He's an inanimate object
他的钱在这不管用
his money's no good here
你在胡说什么  章鱼哥先生
What are you saying, Mr. Squidward
大家的钱在这都管用
Everyone's money is good here
在蟹堡王  我们会服务各式各样的人
At the Krusty Krab, we serves all kinds
我才不帮泡泡接单
I'm not taking an order for a bubble
你必须接
Sure you are
否则我就让你下半生吃不了兜着走
Or I'll fill your life with misery and woe
就算你辞职也一样
Even if you quit
我能接你的单吗
May I take your order?
等等  泡泡人
Wait, Bubble Buddy
我来替你做决定
Let me decide for you
菜单
蟹黄堡
Krabby Patty
双层堡堡
Double Patty Patty
小小蟹黄堡
Krabby Junior Junior
小乱堡
Jumble Small Patty
大三大四大二堡
Junior Senior Sophomore Patty
双层夸脱盎司磅堡
Quarter Ouncer Double Pounder
全都好不错
It's all so good
他只要所有东西都来一份就行
He'll just have one of everything
所有东西来一份
One of everything?
我爱泡泡人
I love Bubble Buddy
泡泡人
章鱼哥  带我们最好的顾客去餐桌
Squidward, show our best customer to his table
泡泡人渴了
Bubble Buddy's thirsty
来杯我们这最好的洗发露怎么样
How about a glass of our finest shampoo
听起来好棒
Sounds great
护发用品来了  先生
Here's your hair care product, sir
泡泡人喜欢弯弯的吸管
Bubble Buddy likes bendy straws
说什么
What's that?
泡泡人说味道很怪
Bubble Buddy says it tastes funny
你觉得呢
What do you think?
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
替顾客着想
Think of the customer
我可真傻
Silly me
给你上成了无糖洗发露
I got the diet shampoo
来了
Here we go
所有东西各一份给泡泡人
One of everything for Bubble Buddy
不行  章鱼哥
Oh, no, Squidward
先等等
Wait
蟹黄堡上面有奶酪
There's cheese on these patties
然后呢
And?
泡泡人乳糖不耐
Bubble Buddy's lactose intolerant
他可不能吃奶酪
He can't eat cheese
我们该怎么办
What should we do?
我们
We?
要不然你就带着这些蟹黄堡再
How about you take these patties and sho--
章鱼哥先生
Mr. Squidward
你放心  泡泡人
Don't worry, Bubble Buddy
章鱼哥会再做一大盘的
Squidward will make a fresh batch
什么
What?
他也对面包过敏
Is he allergic to bread, too?
其实他不喜欢面包皮
Actually, he doesn't like the crust
而且章鱼哥  番茄酱应该在肉饼下面
And Squidward, the ketchup should be under the patty
而且章鱼哥  腌椰菜应该放左边
And Squidward, the pickles should be on the left side
而且章鱼哥  你应该
And Squidward, you should--
而且章鱼哥
and Squidward
and Squidward--
而且章鱼哥
and Squidward
给  所有东西各一份
Here, one of everything
没奶酪  没面包皮
No cheese, no crust
腌椰菜放左边
pickles to the left
四滴番茄酱
four squirts of ketchup
小麦面包  无乳生菜
wheat buns, non-dairy lettuce
人工饲养番茄  嘉年华样式
and farm-raised tomatoes, carnival style
如果还有别的事想要我做的
And, if there's anything else I can do
请  一定要犹豫
please, hesitate to ask
真是太好吃了
That was delicious
钱放桌上了  蟹老板
Money's on the table, Mr. Krabs
再见了  小子们
So long, boys
看吧章鱼哥
You see, Squidward
餐饮行业就是服务至上
the restaurant game is all about service
顾客永远是对的
The customer is always right
记住了  小子
Remember that, lad
你总有一天会像我一样成功的
and you'll be as successful as me one day
你说得对  蟹老板
You're right, Mr. Krabs
这我学到了
I learned my lesson
顺带一提  泡泡人买单了
And by the way, Bubble Buddy picked up the tab
这是什么
What's this?
泡泡钱
Bubble money
起码他们还留了小费
At least they left a tip
我们到了  泡泡人
Here we are, Bubble Buddy
酷乐湖
Goo Lagoon
在这有好多方式可以大玩特玩
There are lots of ways to have fun here
欢迎来到酷乐湖
兄弟  把我埋了
Dudes, bury me
知道我意思了吧
See what I mean?
埋好了
All done
好耶
All right
泡泡人  你把他挖出来
Bubble Buddy, you dig him out
我去买点棉花糖
while I get some cotton candy
别光站那儿啊  兄弟
Don't just stand there, dude
潮快涨过来了
The tide's coming in
兄弟
Dude?
港口公厕
我朋友还在里面
My friend's in there
恭喜你了
Congratulations
摇起来
Shake it
摇起来  对
Shake it, yeah
泡泡屁股摇起来
Shake that bubble butt
好耶
Yeah
我屁股大吗
Is my butt big?
是世界闻名的冲浪游民  邋遢石斑
It's the world famous surf bum, Grubby Grouper
等会见  石斑迷
Later, Groupies
邋遢要去整点大家伙了
Grubby's gotta go catch some gnarly pounders
我不会再洗这只鳍肢了
I'll never wash this flipper again
嗨  珍珍
Hey, Pearl
跟泡泡人握个手吧
Shake hands with Bubble Buddy
什
Wha--
他这是第一次自己上
It's his first time on his own
再次恭喜你们
Once again, congratulations
爆米花  花生
Popcorn, peanuts
此处需等待45分钟
冰镇冷饮
Ice cold drinks
港口公厕
两小时够久了吧
Two hours is long enough
够了
That's it
泡泡人
Hey, Bubble Buddy
你上完了啊
You're finished
他就让我们等一个泡泡
He kept us waiting for a bubble?
那不算什么
That's nothing
他说我们肥
He called us fat
他洗了我的鳍肢
He washed my flipper
他欠了我的钱
He owes me money
他让我提供了优质的服务
He made me provide excellent service
兄弟  他让我经历了涨潮
Dudes, he made me experience high tide
他往我们供水系统里下毒
He poisoned our water supply
烧了我们庄稼
burned our crops
把瘟疫带到了我们家里
and delivered a plague onto our houses
有这回事
He did?
没有
No
可难道我们非得放任他等他这样做吗
But are we just gonna wait around until he does?
我们要推翻东西
I say we tip something over
好
Yeah
现在怎么了
Now what?
抓住救生员
Get the lifeguard
住手
Wait
不要对他施加这种无谓的暴力
Don't waste this senseless violence on him
都是海绵宝宝的那个笨泡泡
It's that stupid bubble of SpongeBob's
导致了这一切的问题
that's causing all the problems
谁挺我
Who's with me?
扎破泡泡
Pop the bubble
各位
Hey, everyone
你们认识过我朋友泡泡人吗
Have you met my friend, Bubble Buddy?
认识
Yes
这是
Is, uh--
开了个针织小组吗
one of those sewing circles?
不
No
介意不要把那些针离得那么近吗
Would you mind not getting so close with those pins?
尖锐物品会让泡泡人不舒服的
Pointy objects make Bubble Buddy uncomfortable
上厕所
海绵宝宝  那个泡泡必须消失
SpongeBob, that bubble's gotta go
不必了
Oh, no
他已经会上厕所了
He already took care of that
还是谢谢关心
But thanks for your concern
不
No
消失成
Go as an
为什么
Why?
你跟那个泡泡就只会惹麻烦
You and that bubble have been nothing but trouble
是时候要结束了
It's time to end it
不
No
我不会让你们
I won't let you
我们走
Here we go
你们抓不到我了
You'll never catch us now
抓不到
Never
抓
Ne--
不到
ver
闹够了吧  海绵宝宝
Enough seahorsing around, SpongeBob
把泡泡给我们
Give us that bubble
扎破泡泡
Pop the bubble
不
No
不行
You can't
他不止是个泡泡
He's not just a bubble
他是个泡泡人
he's a Bubble Buddy
他是我的朋友  我爱他
He's my friend and I love him
你们就没有过很特别的朋友吗
Haven't you ever had a very special friend?
硬币人
Nickel Buddy
我从来没把你花掉
I'll never spend you
古怪消音器
Funny Muffler
肉干兄弟
Jerky Pal
钥匙布布
Booboo Keys
两个一
Snake Eyes
我们爱你
We love you
那你们觉得如何
So, what do you say?
扎破泡泡
Pop the bubble
赶紧把事解决了
Let's get this over with
好让我回家吹竖笛
so I can go home and play my clarinet
不
No
我难道没发言权吗
Don't I get a say in this?
改些时候见吧  海绵宝宝
I'll see you later, SpongeBob
这里的情况越来越怪了
Things are getting a little weird around here
出租车
再见
So long
莱弗埃里克松节快乐
Happy Leif Erikson Day
他是活的
He's alive
当然了
Of course
不然他才讲不出这么好笑的笑话
Otherwise he couldn't tell such funny jokes
我没意见
OK by me
事成了
I'm done
就好像
Seems like
我今早还握着他的泡泡水瓶一样
only this morning I held his bottle
小泡泡爆得好快
They blow up so fast
嗨
Hi